<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Knowledgebase</title>
      <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np</link>
      <description>Last 10 notes on Knowledgebase</description>
      <generator>Quartz -- quartz.jzhao.xyz</generator>
      <item>
    <title>Welcome to my Knowledgebase</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/</guid>
    <description>Hey there! 👋 This is my personal knowledge base, where I document my journey, notes, and learnings in the world of cybersecurity. Here you can explore my write-ups, dive into networking concepts, or just learn alongside me.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 09:23:52 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>OSI Model</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/OSI-Model</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/OSI-Model</guid>
    <description>Abbr: Open Systems Interconnection It has 7 layers: Physical Layer Describes the mechanical/electrical and other means to activate, maintain and deactivate physical connection ...</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 09:23:52 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Port</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/Port</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/Port</guid>
    <description>A port is a numeric identifier within each segment that is used to keep track of specific conversations between a client and server. Ports are assigned and managed by an organization known as the Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers (ICANN).</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 09:23:52 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Socket</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/Socket</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/Socket</guid>
    <description>The combination of the source IP address and source Port number, or the destination IP address and destination Port number is known as a socket. Sockets enable multiple processes, running on a client, to distinguish themselves from each other, and multiple connections to a server process to be distinguished from each other.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 09:23:52 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>TCP IP Model</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/TCP-IP-Model</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/TCP-IP-Model</guid>
    <description>TCP/IP protocol is responsible for guaranteeing reliable delivery of a packet. TCP/IP protocol has 4 layers: Application Layer Represents data to the user, encoding and dialog control Transport Layer Supports communication between various devices across network Internet Layer Determines best path through the network Network Access Layer Controls the devices and media that make up the network The difference between TCP IP Model and OSI Model are given in TCP IP vs OSI Model.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 09:23:52 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>TCP IP vs OSI Model</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/TCP-IP-vs-OSI-Model</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/TCP-IP-vs-OSI-Model</guid>
    <description>While TCP/IP and OSI both are meant to standardize communication in a network, they have some key similarities and differences. TCP/IP model does not describe general functions that are necessary for all networking communications.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 09:23:52 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>TCP</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/TCP</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/TCP</guid>
    <description>Transmission Control Protocol (TCP) is a Transport Layer Protocol that is widely used to ensure reliable and ordered delivery of data over a network. Unlike UDP, TCP is a connection-oriented protocol that establishes a connection between the sender and receiver before data transmission.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 09:23:52 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Transport Layer Protocol</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/Transport-Layer-Protocol</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/Transport-Layer-Protocol</guid>
    <description>Transport Layer is the 4th Layer of OSI Model and 3rd Layer of TCP IP Model. It is responsible for ensuring packets are sent reliably and any missing packets are resent.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 09:23:52 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>UDP</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/UDP</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/UDP</guid>
    <description>User Datagram Protocol (UDP) is a Transport Layer Protocol which is used transferring data over networks. UDP packets each have their own header and payload.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 09:23:52 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>URI, URN and URL</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/URI,-URN-and-URL</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/URI,-URN-and-URL</guid>
    <description>Web resources and web services such as RESTful APIs are identified using a Uniform Resource Identifier (URI). A URI is a string of characters that identifies a specific network resource.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 09:23:52 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>