<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Knowledgebase</title>
      <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np</link>
      <description>Last 10 notes on Knowledgebase</description>
      <generator>Quartz -- quartz.jzhao.xyz</generator>
      <item>
    <title>IPV4 Address</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/IPV4-Address</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/IPV4-Address</guid>
    <description>An IPV4 Address is used to identify each device in a network. It is a logical address of a device on a network. Subnet Mask The subnet mask is used to identify the network on which the host is connected.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 17:47:48 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>IPV6 Address</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/IPV6-Address</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/IPV6-Address</guid>
    <description>IPV6 Address was introduce to overcome the limitations of IPV4 Address. IPv6 addresses are 128 bits in length and written as a string of hexadecimal values.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 17:47:48 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Mac Address</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/Mac-Address</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/Mac-Address</guid>
    <description>A MAC (Media Access Control) address is a unique identifier assigned to a network interface card (NIC) for use in communications within a network segment ...</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 17:47:48 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>NAT</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/NAT</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/NAT</guid>
    <description>NAT abbr. Network Address Translation is the process of translating a private IP Address into public IP Address and vice versa. It is done by the router when a user tries to send a packet to a host not in the network.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 17:47:48 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>OSI Model</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/OSI-Model</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/OSI-Model</guid>
    <description>Abbr: Open Systems Interconnection It has 7 layers: Physical Layer Describes the mechanical/electrical and other means to activate, maintain and deactivate physical connection ...</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 17:47:48 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Port</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/Port</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/Port</guid>
    <description>A port is a numeric identifier within each segment that is used to keep track of specific conversations between a client and server. Ports are assigned and managed by an organization known as the Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers (ICANN).</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 17:47:48 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Socket</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/Socket</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/Socket</guid>
    <description>The combination of the source IP address and source Port number, or the destination IP address and destination Port number is known as a socket. Sockets enable multiple processes, running on a client, to distinguish themselves from each other, and multiple connections to a server process to be distinguished from each other.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 17:47:48 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>TCP IP Model</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/TCP-IP-Model</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/TCP-IP-Model</guid>
    <description>TCP/IP protocol is responsible for guaranteeing reliable delivery of a packet. TCP/IP protocol has 4 layers: Application Layer Represents data to the user, encoding and dialog control Transport Layer Supports communication between various devices across network Internet Layer Determines best path through the network Network Access Layer Controls the devices and media that make up the network The difference between TCP IP Model and OSI Model are given in TCP IP vs OSI Model.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 17:47:48 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>TCP IP vs OSI Model</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/TCP-IP-vs-OSI-Model</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/TCP-IP-vs-OSI-Model</guid>
    <description>While TCP/IP and OSI both are meant to standardize communication in a network, they have some key similarities and differences. TCP/IP model does not describe general functions that are necessary for all networking communications.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 17:47:48 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>TCP</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/TCP</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/TCP</guid>
    <description>Transmission Control Protocol (TCP) is a Transport Layer Protocol that is widely used to ensure reliable and ordered delivery of data over a network. Unlike UDP, TCP is a connection-oriented protocol that establishes a connection between the sender and receiver before data transmission.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 17:47:48 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>