<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Knowledgebase</title>
      <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np</link>
      <description>Last 10 notes on Knowledgebase</description>
      <generator>Quartz -- quartz.jzhao.xyz</generator>
      <item>
    <title>TCP</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/TCP</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/TCP</guid>
    <description>Transmission Control Protocol (TCP) is a Transport Layer Protocol that is widely used to ensure reliable and ordered delivery of data over a network. Unlike UDP, TCP is a connection-oriented protocol that establishes a connection between the sender and receiver before data transmission.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 17:34:43 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Transport Layer Protocol</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/Transport-Layer-Protocol</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/Transport-Layer-Protocol</guid>
    <description>Transport Layer is the 4th Layer of OSI Model and 3rd Layer of TCP IP Model. It is responsible for ensuring packets are sent reliably and any missing packets are resent.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 17:34:43 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>UDP</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/UDP</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/UDP</guid>
    <description>User Datagram Protocol (UDP) is a Transport Layer Protocol which is used transferring data over networks. UDP packets each have their own header and payload.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 17:34:43 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>URI, URN and URL</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/URI,-URN-and-URL</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/URI,-URN-and-URL</guid>
    <description>Web resources and web services such as RESTful APIs are identified using a Uniform Resource Identifier (URI). A URI is a string of characters that identifies a specific network resource.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 17:34:43 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>C2</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC-Level-1/C2</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC-Level-1/C2</guid>
    <description>Command and Control (C2) Infrastructure are a set of programs used to communicate with a victim machine. This is comparable to a Reverse Shell, but is generally more advanced and often communicate via common network protocols, like HTTP, HTTPS and DNS.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 17:34:43 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Fast Flux</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC-Level-1/Fast-Flux</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC-Level-1/Fast-Flux</guid>
    <description>Fast Flux is a DNS technique used by botnets to hide phishing, web proxying, malware delivery, and malware communication activities behind compromised hosts acting as proxies ...</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 17:34:43 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Hash</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC-Level-1/Hash</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC-Level-1/Hash</guid>
    <description>A hash value is a numeric value of a fixed length that uniquely identifies data. It is the result of a hashing algorithm. Common Hash Types MD5 (Message Digest, defined by RFC 1321 MD5 is a widely used cryptographic hash function with a 128-bit hash value.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 17:34:43 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Pyramid of Pain</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC-Level-1/Pyramid-of-Pain</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC-Level-1/Pyramid-of-Pain</guid>
    <description>Pyramid of Pain is a concept which is used to determine the level of difficulty it will cause for an adversary to change the indicators associated with them, and their campaign ...</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 17:34:43 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>SOC</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC-Level-1/SOC</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC-Level-1/SOC</guid>
    <description>Security Operations Center (SOC) is a team of IT security professionals tasked with monitoring, preventing , detecting , investigating, and responding to threats within a company’s ...</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 17:34:43 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Welcome</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/</guid>
    <description>Hey there! 👋 This is my personal cybersecurity knowledge base, where I document my journey, notes, and learnings in the world of cybersecurity. Whether you’re here to explore Hack The Box (HTB) write-ups, dive into networking concepts, or just learn alongside me, you’re in the right place! What’s Here? Hack The Box (HTB): Notes, write-ups, and methodologies from HTB machines and challenges.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 17:34:43 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>