<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Knowledgebase</title>
      <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np</link>
      <description>Last 10 notes on Knowledgebase</description>
      <generator>Quartz -- quartz.jzhao.xyz</generator>
      <item>
    <title>Socket</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/Socket</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/Socket</guid>
    <description>The combination of the source IP address and source Port number, or the destination IP address and destination Port number is known as a socket. Sockets enable multiple processes, running on a client, to distinguish themselves from each other, and multiple connections to a server process to be distinguished from each other.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 09:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>TCP IP Model</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/TCP-IP-Model</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/TCP-IP-Model</guid>
    <description>TCP/IP protocol is responsible for guaranteeing reliable delivery of a packet. TCP/IP protocol has 4 layers: Application Layer Represents data to the user, encoding and dialog control Transport Layer Supports communication between various devices across network Internet Layer Determines best path through the network Network Access Layer Controls the devices and media that make up the network The difference between TCP IP Model and OSI Model are given in TCP IP vs OSI Model.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 09:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>TCP IP vs OSI Model</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/TCP-IP-vs-OSI-Model</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/TCP-IP-vs-OSI-Model</guid>
    <description>While TCP/IP and OSI both are meant to standardize communication in a network, they have some key similarities and differences. TCP/IP model does not describe general functions that are necessary for all networking communications.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 09:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>TCP</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/TCP</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/TCP</guid>
    <description>Transmission Control Protocol (TCP) is a Transport Layer Protocol that is widely used to ensure reliable and ordered delivery of data over a network. Unlike UDP, TCP is a connection-oriented protocol that establishes a connection between the sender and receiver before data transmission.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 09:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Transport Layer Protocol</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/Transport-Layer-Protocol</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/Transport-Layer-Protocol</guid>
    <description>Transport Layer is the 4th Layer of OSI Model and 3rd Layer of TCP IP Model. It is responsible for ensuring packets are sent reliably and any missing packets are resent.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 09:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>UDP</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/UDP</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/UDP</guid>
    <description>User Datagram Protocol (UDP) is a Transport Layer Protocol which is used transferring data over networks. UDP packets each have their own header and payload.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 09:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>URI, URN and URL</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/URI,-URN-and-URL</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/URI,-URN-and-URL</guid>
    <description>Web resources and web services such as RESTful APIs are identified using a Uniform Resource Identifier (URI). A URI is a string of characters that identifies a specific network resource.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 09:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>C2</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC-Level-1/C2</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC-Level-1/C2</guid>
    <description>Command and Control (C2) Infrastructure are a set of programs used to communicate with a victim machine. This is comparable to a Reverse Shell, but is generally more advanced and often communicate via common network protocols, like HTTP, HTTPS and DNS.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 09:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Fast Flux</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC-Level-1/Fast-Flux</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC-Level-1/Fast-Flux</guid>
    <description>Fast Flux is a DNS technique used by botnets to hide phishing, web proxying, malware delivery, and malware communication activities behind compromised hosts acting as proxies ...</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 09:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Hash</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC-Level-1/Hash</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC-Level-1/Hash</guid>
    <description>A hash value is a numeric value of a fixed length that uniquely identifies data. It is the result of a hashing algorithm. Common Hash Types MD5 (Message Digest, defined by RFC 1321 MD5 is a widely used cryptographic hash function with a 128-bit hash value.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 09:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>