<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Knowledgebase</title>
      <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np</link>
      <description>Last 10 notes on Knowledgebase</description>
      <generator>Quartz -- quartz.jzhao.xyz</generator>
      <item>
    <title>MITRE ATT&amp;CK Matrix</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/MITRE-ATT-and-CK-Matrix</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/MITRE-ATT-and-CK-Matrix</guid>
    <description>What is ATT&amp;CK Matrix? 🤔 MITRE ATT&amp;CK Matrix is a visualization method used to classify and see attack methods of cyber attackers. Matrices can be customized for almost any subject and turned into useful visuals.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 20:23:27 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>MITRE ATT&amp;CK Mitigations</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/MITRE-ATT-and-CK-Mitigations</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/MITRE-ATT-and-CK-Mitigations</guid>
    <description>What are Mitigations? Mitigations refers to the measures and actions that can be taken in response to the techniques in the MITRE ATT&amp;CK matrix. Each mitigation has a unique ID, name and description that provides clear understanding about them.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 20:23:27 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>MITRE ATT&amp;CK Tactics</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/MITRE-ATT-and-CK-Tactics</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/MITRE-ATT-and-CK-Tactics</guid>
    <description>What is Tactic? Tactic expresses the purpose of the cyber attacker and the reason for his action. Tactics are one of the most important MITRE ATT&amp;CK Framework components used to group cyber attacker behaviors and see the attack steps.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 20:23:27 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>MITRE ATT&amp;CK Technics &amp; Sub-Techniques</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/MITRE-ATT-and-CK-Technics--and--Sub-Techniques</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/MITRE-ATT-and-CK-Technics--and--Sub-Techniques</guid>
    <description>What are Techniques and Sub-Techniques? The tactics within the matrix only show what the attackers aim and do not contain detailed information about the attacker’s attack method ...</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 20:23:27 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Masquerading</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/Masquerading</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/Masquerading</guid>
    <description>Masquerading occurs when the name or location of an object, legitimate or malicious, is manipulated or abused for the sake of evading defenses and observation ...</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 20:23:27 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Network Propagation</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/Network-Propagation</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/Network-Propagation</guid>
    <description>After a device is exploited in a network, the adversary spreads its access through the network. Exploiting more devices in the same network becomes a lot more easier because usually: Credentials to other devices may be insecurely stored on host Host might have exclusive access to other devices such as printers and storages, not open to public Hence, the attacker would set up a base on one of the systems to act as their pivot point and use it to gather information about the internal network.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 20:23:27 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>OSINT</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/OSINT</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/OSINT</guid>
    <description>Open source intelligence (OSINT) is the act of gathering and analyzing publicly available data for intelligence purposes.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 20:23:27 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>OWASP</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/OWASP</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/OWASP</guid>
    <description>The Open Web Application Security Project (OWASP) is a non-profit foundation dedicated to improving software security. Without a doubt, OWASP is one of the best resources for information on web application security.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 20:23:27 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Pass the Hash Attack</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/Pass-the-Hash-Attack</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/Pass-the-Hash-Attack</guid>
    <description>A Pass-the-Hash (PtH) attack is a technique where an attacker captures a password Hash (as opposed to the password characters) and then passes it through for authentication and lateral ...</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 20:23:27 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Phishing</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/Phishing</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/Phishing</guid>
    <description>Phishing is a form of social engineering and a scam where attackers deceive people into revealing sensitive information or installing malware such as viruses, worms, adware, or ...</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 20:23:27 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>