<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Knowledgebase</title>
      <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np</link>
      <description>Last 10 notes on Knowledgebase</description>
      <generator>Quartz -- quartz.jzhao.xyz</generator>
      <item>
    <title>SOC</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/SOC</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/SOC</guid>
    <description>Security Operations Center (SOC) is a team of IT security professionals tasked with monitoring, preventing , detecting , investigating, and responding to threats within a company’s ...</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 14:26:33 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Timestomping</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/Timestomping</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/Timestomping</guid>
    <description>Timestomping is a technique that modifies the timestamps of a file (the modify, access, create, and change times), often to mimic files that are in the same folder and blend malicious ...</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 14:26:33 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Unified Kill Chain</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/Unified-Kill-Chain</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/Unified-Kill-Chain</guid>
    <description>The unified kill chain aims to complement (not compete with) other cybersecurity kill chain frameworks, such as The Cyber Kill Chain. It states that there are 18 phases to an attack: Everything from Reconnaissance to data exfiltration and understanding an attacker’s motive.</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 14:26:33 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Watering Hole</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/Watering-Hole</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/Watering-Hole</guid>
    <description>A watering hole attack is a targeted attack designed to aim at a specific group of people by compromising the website they are usually visiting and then redirecting them to the malicious ...</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 14:26:33 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Wireshark</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/Wireshark</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/Wireshark</guid>
    <description>Tool used to analyze network traffic. The GOAT.</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 14:26:33 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>fuzzy hashing</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/fuzzy-hashing</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/SOC/fuzzy-hashing</guid>
    <description>Fuzzy hashing helps us to perform similarity analysis - match two files with minor differences based on the fuzzy hash values. One of the examples of fuzzy hashing is the usage of SSDeep.</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 14:26:33 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Welcome to my Knowledgebase</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/</guid>
    <description>👋 Hi there! Welcome to my digital knowledge base—a curated collection of my learning journey in cybersecurity, networking, AI, and more. This is where I document my notes, methodologies, and experiments as I explore the world of technology.</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 14:26:33 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>TCP IP Model</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/TCP-IP-Model</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/TCP-IP-Model</guid>
    <description>TCP/IP protocol is responsible for guaranteeing reliable delivery of a packet. TCP/IP protocol has 4 layers: Application Layer Represents data to the user, encoding and dialog control Transport Layer Supports communication between various devices across network Internet Layer Determines best path through the network Network Access Layer Controls the devices and media that make up the network The difference between TCP IP Model and OSI Model are given in TCP IP vs OSI Model.</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 14:26:33 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>TCP IP vs OSI Model</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/TCP-IP-vs-OSI-Model</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/TCP-IP-vs-OSI-Model</guid>
    <description>While TCP/IP and OSI both are meant to standardize communication in a network, they have some key similarities and differences. TCP/IP model does not describe general functions that are necessary for all networking communications.</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 14:26:33 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>TCP</title>
    <link>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/TCP</link>
    <guid>https://knowledgebase.prashantgiri360.com.np/Networking/TCP</guid>
    <description>Transmission Control Protocol (TCP) is a Transport Layer Protocol that is widely used to ensure reliable and ordered delivery of data over a network. Unlike UDP, TCP is a connection-oriented protocol that establishes a connection between the sender and receiver before data transmission.</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 14:26:33 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>